<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Recent &amp; Upcoming Events | CONECT | Computational Neuroscience Center @ INT</title>
    <link>https://conect-int.github.io/event/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://conect-int.github.io/event/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Recent &amp; Upcoming Events</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2023 16:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://conect-int.github.io/media/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Recent &amp; Upcoming Events</title>
      <link>https://conect-int.github.io/event/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>2023-01-05 : CONECT seminar by Guillaume Dumas</title>
      <link>https://conect-int.github.io/talk/2023-01-05-conect-seminar-by-guillaume-dumas/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2023 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://conect-int.github.io/talk/2023-01-05-conect-seminar-by-guillaume-dumas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;During this CONECT seminar, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.extrospection.eu&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Guillaume Dumas&lt;/a&gt; will present his recent work on &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;Multilevel Development of Cognitive Abilities in an Artificial Neural Network&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rdquo;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several neuronal mechanisms have been proposed to account for the formation of cognitive abilities through postnatal interactions with the physical and socio-cultural environment. Here, we introduce a three-level computational model of information processing and acquisition of cognitive abilities. We propose minimal architectural requirements to build these levels and how the parameters affect their performance and relationships. The first sensorimotor level handles local nonconscious processing, here during a visual classification task. The second level or cognitive level globally integrates the information from multiple local processors via long-ranged connections and synthesizes it in a global, but still nonconscious manner. The third and cognitively highest level handles the information globally and consciously. It is based on the Global Neuronal Workspace (GNW) theory and is referred to as conscious level. We use trace and delay conditioning tasks to, respectively, challenge the second and third levels. Results first highlight the necessity of epigenesis through selection and stabilization of synapses at both local and global scales to allow the network to solve the first two tasks. At the global scale, dopamine appears necessary to properly provide credit assignment despite the temporal delay between perception and reward. At the third level, the presence of interneurons becomes necessary to maintain a self-sustained representation within the GNW in the absence of sensory input. Finally, while balanced spontaneous intrinsic activity facilitates epigenesis at both local and global scales, the balanced excitatory-inhibitory ratio increases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mor info: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.pnas.org/doi/10.1073/pnas.2201304119&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://www.pnas.org/doi/10.1073/pnas.2201304119&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keywords: computational biology, dynamical systems, medical machine learning (ML), neuroscience, AI ethics&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Guillaume Dumas is an Associate Professor of Computational Psychiatry in the Faculty of Medicine at the Université de Montréal, and the Principle Investigator of the Precision Psychiatry and Social Physiology laboratory at the CHU Sainte-Justine Research Center. He holds the IVADO professorship for “AI in Mental Health”, and the FRQS J1 in “AI and Digital Health”.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2022-11-24 : CONECT seminar by Bruno Cessac</title>
      <link>https://conect-int.github.io/talk/2022-11-24-conect-seminar-by-bruno-cessac/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2022 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://conect-int.github.io/talk/2022-11-24-conect-seminar-by-bruno-cessac/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;During this CONECT seminar, &lt;a href=&#34;https://team.inria.fr/biovision/bruno-cessac/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Bruno Cessac&lt;/a&gt; did present his recent work on &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;Retinal processing: Insights from mathematical modelling&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rdquo;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The retina is the entrance of the visual system. Although based on common biophysical principles, the dynamics of retinal neurons are quite different from their cortical counterparts, raising interesting problems for modellers. In this paper, I address some mathematically stated questions in this spirit, discussing, in particular: (1) How could lateral amacrine cell connectivity shape the spatio-temporal spike response of retinal ganglion cells? (2) How could spatio-temporal stimuli correlations and retinal network dynamics shape the spike train correlations at the output of the retina? These questions are addressed, first, introducing a mathematically tractable model of the layered retina, integrating amacrine cells’ lateral connectivity and piecewise linear rectification, allowing for computing the retinal ganglion cells receptive field together with the voltage and spike correlations of retinal ganglion cells resulting from the amacrine cells networks. Then, I review some recent results showing how the concept of spatio-temporal Gibbs distributions and linear response theory can be used to characterize the collective spike response to a spatio-temporal stimulus of a set of retinal ganglion cells, coupled via effective interactions corresponding to the amacrine cells network. On these bases, I briefly discuss several potential consequences of these results at the cortical level.
Keywords: retinal network; visual system; spatio-temporal spike correlations; linear response; non stationarity&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    My research was initially modeling and analysis of large sized dynamical systems arising in various fields such as physics, biology, sociology, computers networks. I have worked on subjects such as self-organized criticality, linear response in chaotic systems, social networks, communications networks. My main interest concerns neuronal networks dynamics. I have developed methods combining dynamical systems theory, statistical physics and ergodic theory allowing to classify dynamics arising in canonical neuronal networks models like integrate and fire models or firing rate models. I have applied these methods for the study of synaptic and intrinsic plasticity, dynamical learning, spike coding, spike train statistics analysis, mean-field dynamics. I am now involved in developing models for the visual system, especially the retina, as well as numerical methods and software for neuroscientists.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2022-10-05 : CONECT workshop &#34;Higher-order interactions in brain networks: from theory to data analysis&#34;</title>
      <link>https://conect-int.github.io/talk/2022-10-05-conect-workshop-higher-order-interactions-in-brain-networks-from-theory-to-data-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2022 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://conect-int.github.io/talk/2022-10-05-conect-workshop-higher-order-interactions-in-brain-networks-from-theory-to-data-analysis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are pleased to invite you to a mini-workshop organized as a scientific activity of the Computational Neuroscience Center (CONECT) of the INT focused on &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Higher-order interactions in brain networks: from theory to data analysis&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Two speakers will present their work from two complementary theoretical perspectives, emerged from recent advances in network science (Giovanni Petri) and information theory (Daniele Marinazzo).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in the topic and/or want to learn something new, please join us in the &lt;strong&gt;salle Laurent Vinay&lt;/strong&gt; on &lt;strong&gt;Wednesday 5th October 2022&lt;/strong&gt; at &lt;strong&gt;14:30&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are the titles and abstracts of the two presentations:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;giovanni-petri--turin-univ&#34;&gt;Giovanni Petri  (Turin Univ)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://lordgrilo.github.io/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://lordgrilo.github.io/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://scholar.google.co.uk/citations?user=jb__2PIAAAAJ&amp;amp;hl=en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://scholar.google.co.uk/citations?user=jb__2PIAAAAJ&amp;hl=en&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Title: &lt;strong&gt;Between higher-order mechanisms and phenomena&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract: Complex networks have become the main paradigm for modelling the dynamics of complex interacting systems. However, networks are intrinsically limited to describing pairwise interactions, whereas real-world systems are often characterized by higher-order interactions involving groups of three or more units. Higher-order structures, such as hypergraphs and simplicial complexes, are therefore a better tool to map the real organization of many social, biological and man-made systems. At the same time, higher-order observables, typically topological or information-theoretic in nature and often sharing the same simplicial language, have been gathering  attention for their capacity to capture properties of complex systems that are invisible to standard statistical descriptions. This had led to a certain confusion between these two facets, mechanisms on one side, phenomena on the other. Here, using recent examples from both computational modeling and neuroimaging analysis, I highlight collective behaviours induced by higher-order interactions, their interface with recent advances in topological data analysis, and finally outline three key challenges for the physics of higher-order complex systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;daniele-marinazzo-ghent-univ&#34;&gt;Daniele Marinazzo (Ghent Univ)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://users.ugent.be/~dmarinaz/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://users.ugent.be/~dmarinaz/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://scholar.google.com/citations?user=OJbWSLoAAAAJ&amp;amp;hl=en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://scholar.google.com/citations?user=OJbWSLoAAAAJ&amp;hl=en&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Title: Two  is company, three is a party, and how not to get lost in big parties: practical considerations on higher-order data analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract: I will make the case for looking for high-order interactions in (neural) data, and for trying to do so in a principled yet feasible way (who needs yet another axiom?).
I will then loop back and show how we can find low-order descriptors of high-order interactions (we&amp;rsquo;re not good in figuring things in high dimensions).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2022-09-08 : CONECT seminar by Charlie Sexton</title>
      <link>https://conect-int.github.io/talk/2022-09-08-conect-seminar-by-charlie-sexton/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2022 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://conect-int.github.io/talk/2022-09-08-conect-seminar-by-charlie-sexton/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;During this CONECT seminar, &lt;a href=&#34;https://psychologicalsciences.unimelb.edu.au/research/msps-research-groups/timing/lab/people#&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Charlie Sexton&lt;/a&gt; will present his recent work on &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;Spike-timing dependent plasticity among multiple layers of motion-sensitive neurons: a feedforward mechanism for motion extrapolation&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rdquo;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ability of the brain to represent the external world in real-time is impacted by the fact that neural processing takes time. Because neural delays accumulate as information progresses through the visual system, representations encoded at each hierarchical level are based upon input that is progressively outdated with respect to the external world. This is particularly relevant to the task of localizing a moving object – because the object’s location changes with time, neural representations of its location potentially lag behind its true location. It has therefore been proposed that the visual system utilizes the predictive nature of motion to extrapolate moving objects along their trajectory. Burkitt and Hogendoorn (2021, &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1523/JNEUROSCI.2017-20.2021&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1523/JNEUROSCI.2017-20.2021&lt;/a&gt;) showed how spike-timing dependent plasticity (STDP) can achieve motion extrapolation in a two-layer, feedforward network of velocity-tuned neurons, by shifting the receptive-fields of second-layer neurons in the opposite direction to a moving stimulus. The current study extends this work by implementing two important changes to the network to bring it more into line with biology: we expanded the network to multiple layers to reflect the depth of the visual hierarchy, and we implemented more realistic synaptic time-courses. We examine the degree to which STDP can facilitate compensation of neural delays across six layers, and show that the multi-layer network achieves cumulative compensation comparable in magnitude to the delays incurred in visual processing. We also explore the effect of additional delays imposed on the network by the integration time of the membrane potential.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    More about Charlie: So far in my PhD I have looked at how spike-timing dependent plasticity (STDP) can shift feedforward connection strengths between levels of the visual hierarchy, such that higher levels encode moving objects further along their trajectory (as a mechanism for motion extrapolation). The project began with a paper by my supervisors, Hinze Hogendoorn and Tony Burkitt: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jneurosci.org/content/41/20/4428.abstract&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://www.jneurosci.org/content/41/20/4428.abstract&lt;/a&gt;. I have been working on extending this model network to have 6 layers to see the combined effect of plasticity at several visual areas. I will attach my abstract for my ECVP talk here.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2022-06-20: CONECT at the CENTURI summer school</title>
      <link>https://conect-int.github.io/talk/2022-06-20-conect-at-the-centuri-summer-school/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2022 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://conect-int.github.io/talk/2022-06-20-conect-at-the-centuri-summer-school/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;title-neural-computation-through-population-dynamics&#34;&gt;Title: Neural computation through population dynamics&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;The CENTURI &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/SummerSchool?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;#SummerSchool&lt;/a&gt; 2022 has been launched this morning ! Rosa Cossart has welcomed all the participants this morning.👾&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Excited to begin these two weeks of transfer of knowledge and deep thinking at &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/univamu?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;@univamu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;!👏&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;For more info➡️&lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/K2oyuQWsmb&#34;&gt;https://t.co/K2oyuQWsmb&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/bAldJeyssj&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/bAldJeyssj&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; CENTURI - Turing Centre for Living Systems (@centuri_ls) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/centuri_ls/status/1538893493828997123?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;June 20, 2022&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Program in construction - you can already check the program of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://centuri-livingsystems.org/centuri-summer-school-2022/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;summer school&lt;/a&gt; (June 20 - July 01, 2022)!
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;question&#34;&gt;Question&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How does neural population dynamics relate to behaviorally-relevant computations?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;challenge&#34;&gt;Challenge&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At any given instant, hundreds of billions of cells in our brains are lighting up in a complicated yet highly coordinated manner to give rise to our thoughts, percepts, and movements. A single neuron may be connected to thousands of other cells, sending out and receiving information through electrical impulses called spikes. From an engineering perspective, these spikes form a signal that may be viewed as a series of ones and zeros rapidly unfolding in time. Altogether, these signals reflect the ongoing computations taking place inside the nervous system, and as such, constitute a window into the brain’s inner workings. Recent advances in recording techniques have allowed experimenters to collect data from hundreds to thousands of neurons simultaneously while animals perform simple tasks. Dealing with such high-dimensional data poses important technical challenges that require elaborate methods for data mining and analysis. In this project, students will deal with datasets of increasing complexity and develop a set of analyses to extract meaningful information from the data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;type-of-data&#34;&gt;Type of data&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data that will be shared by the teaching staff, under the BIDS standard data organization which is currently being extended to electrophysiology data by the members of the INT and the CONECT team. The data we will use consists of:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;publicly available recordings from the dorsomedial frontal cortex of NHPs performing a time-interval reproduction task (&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jazlab/Meirhaeghe2021&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://github.com/jazlab/Meirhaeghe2021&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;publicly available recordings from the motor cortex (M1/PMd) during an instructed reach-to-grasp task (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nature.com/articles/sdata201855&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://www.nature.com/articles/sdata201855&lt;/a&gt;, available at the following URL in BIDS: &lt;a href=&#34;https://gin.g-node.org/sprenger/multielectrode_grasp/src/bep_animalephys&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://gin.g-node.org/sprenger/multielectrode_grasp/src/bep_animalephys&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.biorxiv.org/content/10.1101/2021.03.30.437692v5&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://www.biorxiv.org/content/10.1101/2021.03.30.437692v5&lt;/a&gt; : V1, gratings-like, natural stimulations : extracellular electrophy recordings in cat V1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;methods&#34;&gt;Methods&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data visualisation, neural decoding, principal component analysis, kinematic and geometric analyses of neural trajectories in high-dimensional space, hypothesis-testing, null distributions and statistics&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2022-05-12 : A CONECT seminar &#34;Global organization of neuronal activity only requires unstructured local connectivity&#34; (David Dahmen)</title>
      <link>https://conect-int.github.io/talk/2022-05-12-a-conect-seminar-global-organization-of-neuronal-activity-only-requires-unstructured-local-connectivity-david-dahmen/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://conect-int.github.io/talk/2022-05-12-a-conect-seminar-global-organization-of-neuronal-activity-only-requires-unstructured-local-connectivity-david-dahmen/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;During this CONECT seminar, &lt;a href=&#34;https://scholar.google.com/citations?user=AZa4K5QAAAAJ&amp;amp;hl=fr&amp;amp;oi=ao&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;David Dahmen&lt;/a&gt; did present his recent work on &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;Global organization of neuronal activity only requires unstructured local connectivity&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rdquo;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/35049496/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Dahmen D, Layer M, Deutz L, Dąbrowska PA, Voges N, von Papen M, Brochier T, Riehle A, Diesmann M, Grün S, Helias M. Elife. 2022 Jan 20;11:e68422&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Dr. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fz-juelich.de/SharedDocs/Personen/INM/INM-6/EN/staff/Dahmen_David.html?nn=724620&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;David Dahmen&lt;/a&gt; is a PostDoc at the Research Centre Jülich (Institute of Neuroscience and Medicine (INM-6), Computational and Systems Neuroscience &amp;amp; Institute for Advanced Simulation (IAS-6), Theoretical Neuroscience &amp;amp; JARA-Institut Brain structure-function relationships (INM-10)).
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2022-03-04 : INT Seminar - &#34;Unifying Different Psychometric Methods : Theory and Experiment&#34; (Jonathan Vacher)</title>
      <link>https://conect-int.github.io/talk/2022-03-04-int-seminar-unifying-different-psychometric-methods-theory-and-experiment-jonathan-vacher/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2022 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://conect-int.github.io/talk/2022-03-04-int-seminar-unifying-different-psychometric-methods-theory-and-experiment-jonathan-vacher/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;During a seminar at the Institute of Neurosciences Timone in Marseille, &lt;a href=&#34;https://jonathanvacher.github.io/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Jonathan Vacher&lt;/a&gt; will present his recent work on &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;Unifying Different Psychometric Methods : Theory and Experiment&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rdquo;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The two-alternative forced choice (2AFC) paradigm is one of the main methods used to measure perceptual thresholds and biases. Measurements from a 2AFC experiment can be modelled using signal detection theory (SDT) from which the psychometric function can be derived theoretically. Recent efforts to combine SDT with Bayesian probabilities has linked thresholds and biases to hypothesized prior knowledge and optimal encoding/decoding [1]. From another perspective, the maximum likelihood difference scaling (MLDS) paradigm is a more recent method that allows the experimenter to estimate a perceptual scale that links a physical property to a psychological dimension [2]. Such a perceptual scale is obtained from the comparison of relative differences between pairs of stimuli. Here again, the underlying model can be understood in terms of SDT and Bayesian probabilities. However, no comparison between MLDS and 2AFC measurements has been performed yet. Here, we introduce the theory that unifies those measurements and we present some preliminary experimental results. In this context, we further explore how MLDS measurements could help to understand the perception of more complex textures generated from the statistic of deep neural network features [3].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[1] Wei, X. X., &amp;amp; Stocker, A. A. (2017). Lawful relation between perceptual bias and discriminability. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences, 114(38), 10244-10249.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[2] Maloney, L. T., &amp;amp; Yang, J. N. (2003). Maximum likelihood difference scaling. Journal of Vision, 3(8):5, 573-585.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[3] Vacher, J. &amp;amp; Davila, A., Kohn, A. &amp;amp; Coen-Cagli, R. (2021). Texture Interpolation for Probing Visual Perception. Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems, 33.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Dr. &lt;a href=&#34;https://jonathanvacher.github.io/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Jonathan Vacher&lt;/a&gt; was a student at École Normale Supérieure de Cachan (now &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ens-paris-saclay.fr/en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Saclay&lt;/a&gt;) where he pursued a degree in mathematics and applied mathematics. He completed his bachelor&amp;rsquo;s and master&amp;rsquo;s degree with a specialty in computational imaging and machine learning (&lt;a href=&#34;http://math.ens-paris-saclay.fr/version-francaise/formations/master-mva/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Master MVA&lt;/a&gt;). He started a multidisciplinary PhD in mathematics (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dauphine.fr/en/research/research-centers/ceremade-umr-7534.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Paris Dauphine University, CEREMADE)&lt;/a&gt; and neuroscience (&lt;a href=&#34;https://neuropsi.cnrs.fr/fr/icn/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CNRS, UNIC&lt;/a&gt;) under the supervision of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gpeyre.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Gabriel Peyré&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.unic.cnrs-gif.fr/people/cyril_monier/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Cyril Monier&lt;/a&gt;. Then, Jonathan was a postdoc at Albert Einstein College of Medicine in New-York between 2017 and 2020 while initiating a collaboration with Pascal Mamassian from the Laboratoire des Systèmes Perceptifs ()École Normale Supérieure de Paris) where he is currently a postdoc.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2022-02-24 : CONECT Seminar - &#34;Explainable AI for computational auditory neurosciences&#34; (Etienne Thoret)</title>
      <link>https://conect-int.github.io/talk/2022-02-24-conect-seminar-explainable-ai-for-computational-auditory-neurosciences-etienne-thoret/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2022 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://conect-int.github.io/talk/2022-02-24-conect-seminar-explainable-ai-for-computational-auditory-neurosciences-etienne-thoret/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Etienne Thoret (ILCB/PRISM/LIS/AMU) kindly accepted to present his research project during our novel series of CONECT-core © seminars (=seminars open to all but focused on the core theoretical scientific questions of the CONECT members):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Explainable AI for computational auditory neurosciences&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Machine learning and deep neural networks have been raised as compelling models to simulate a broad range of tasks on signals: from classification of sound events to the prediction of human physiological state from electrophysiological data. But what do we really understand about these models and how do they process the information they have been trained to process? As users, we often use them as tools without precisely understanding their mechanistic and representational underpinnings. In this talk, I&amp;rsquo;ll present recent works on how we can take part of these computational systems to answer fundamental research mysteries on auditory perception, speech production and cerebral processing. Beyond acoustics and sound perception, these techniques can find applications for the modeling of a variety of systems, including computational vision in robotics, haptics and clinical applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021-12-10 : CONECT seminar - &#34;Sequence anticipation and STDP emerge from a voltage-based predictive learning rule&#34; (Matteo Saponati)</title>
      <link>https://conect-int.github.io/talk/2021-12-10-conect-seminar-sequence-anticipation-and-stdp-emerge-from-a-voltage-based-predictive-learning-rule-matteo-saponati/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Dec 2021 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://conect-int.github.io/talk/2021-12-10-conect-seminar-sequence-anticipation-and-stdp-emerge-from-a-voltage-based-predictive-learning-rule-matteo-saponati/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;During a seminar at the Institute of Neurosciences Timone in Marseille, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/matteosaponati&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Matteo Saponati&lt;/a&gt;, will present his recent work showing that &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;Sequence anticipation and STDP emerge from a voltage-based predictive learning rule&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rdquo;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intelligent behavior depends on the brain’s ability to anticipate future events. However, the learning rules that enable neurons to predict and fire ahead of sensory inputs remain largely unknown. We propose a plasticity rule based on predictive processing, where the neuron learns a low-rank model of the synaptic input dynamics in its membrane potential. Neurons thereby amplify those synapses that maximally predict other synaptic inputs based on their temporal relations, which provide a solution to an optimization problem that can be implemented at the single-neuron level using only local information. Consequently, neurons learn sequences over long timescales and shift their spikes towards the first inputs in a sequence. We show that this mechanism can explain the development of anticipatory motion signaling and recall in the visual system. Furthermore, we demonstrate that the learning rule gives rise to several experimentally observed STDP (spike-timing-dependent plasticity) mechanisms. These findings suggest prediction as a guiding principle to orchestrate learning and synaptic plasticity in single neurons.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.biorxiv.org/content/10.1101/2021.10.31.466667v1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://www.biorxiv.org/content/10.1101/2021.10.31.466667v1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;when: Friday 10th of December at 11am&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;where: Salle Laurent Vinay at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.int.univ-amu.fr/contact&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Institute of Neurosciences Timone&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/matteosaponati&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Matteo Saponati&lt;/a&gt; is a PhD candidate at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.esi-frankfurt.de/research/vinck-lab/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Ernst Strüngmann Institute (ESI) for Neuroscience - IMPRS for Neural Circuits&lt;/a&gt;.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021-06-17: CONECT meeting #3</title>
      <link>https://conect-int.github.io/talk/2021-06-17-conect-meeting-#3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://conect-int.github.io/talk/2021-06-17-conect-meeting-#3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There will be a third meeting of the CONECT group for the Thursday meeting devoted to the kick-off of these initiatives for INT3. It will consist of an internal meeting (14:00-15:00) and of a talk open to the institute (15:00-16:00).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021-05-27: CONECT meeting - talk by Matthias Pessiglione</title>
      <link>https://conect-int.github.io/talk/2021-05-27-conect-meeting-talk-by-matthias-pessiglione/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://conect-int.github.io/talk/2021-05-27-conect-meeting-talk-by-matthias-pessiglione/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is the second meeting of the CONECT group for the Thursday meeting devoted to the kick-off of these initiatives for INT3. It consists of an internal meeting (14:00-15:00) and of a talk open to the institute (15:00-16:00) by &lt;a href=&#34;https://insb.cnrs.fr/fr/personne/mathias-pessiglione&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Matthias Pessiglione (INSB)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;14:00 - 15:00  coordination on scientific perimeter &amp;amp; objectives&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;15:00 - 16:00 - scientific presentation by &lt;a href=&#34;https://insb.cnrs.fr/fr/personne/mathias-pessiglione&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Matthias Pessiglione (INSB)&lt;/a&gt; on his recent work :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Computational approach to motivational disorders&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a preview in this paper : &lt;a href=&#34;https://academic.oup.com/brain/article/141/3/629/4675073&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Why not try harder? Computational approach to motivation deficits in neuro-psychiatric diseases&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;of related interest &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.odilejacob.fr/catalogue/sciences/neurosciences/vacances-de-momo-sapiens_9782738151742.php&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Les Vacances de Momo Sapiens &lt;/a&gt; (see the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lemonde.fr/sciences/article/2021/05/25/nos-comportements-automatiques-constitutent-l-essentiel-de-nos-actions_6081429_1650684.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Le Monde interview on that book&lt;/a&gt; )&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zoom link  &lt;a href=&#34;https://univ-amu-fr.zoom.us/j/91200617032?pwd=WHRWNy9kNXoyQWZhUHMzS0RzSW1udz09&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://univ-amu-fr.zoom.us/j/91200617032?pwd=WHRWNy9kNXoyQWZhUHMzS0RzSW1udz09&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021-04-29: CONECT kick-off - talk by Rufin van Rullen</title>
      <link>https://conect-int.github.io/talk/2021-04-29-conect-kick-off-talk-by-rufin-van-rullen/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://conect-int.github.io/talk/2021-04-29-conect-kick-off-talk-by-rufin-van-rullen/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;First meeting of the CONECT group for the Thursday meeting devoted to the kick-off of these initiatives for INT3. It consists of an internal meeting (14:00-15:00) and of a talk open to the institute (15:00-16:00).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;14:00 - 15:00  coordination on scientific perimeter &amp;amp; objectives&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;presentation of the working document / round table to discuss these points&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;means of action / operationalization :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Master 2 scholarship (call for topics / we arrive with proposals + application, then selection jury) - possibility of a 3 months extension to arrive at 9 months&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;forecast student training day - 2022&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;15:00 - 15:30 - pause / café&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;15:30 - 16:30 - scientific presentation by &lt;a href=&#34;http://cerco.cnrs.fr/pagesp/rufin/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Rufin van Rullen&lt;/a&gt; on his recent work :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;R VanRullen, A Alamia&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/2104.05575&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;GAttANet: Global attention agreement for convolutional neural networks&lt;/a&gt; - arXiv preprint arXiv:2104.05575, 2021&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021-04-23 : PhDProgram course in computational neuroscience</title>
      <link>https://conect-int.github.io/talk/2021-04-23-phdprogram-course-in-computational-neuroscience/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://conect-int.github.io/talk/2021-04-23-phdprogram-course-in-computational-neuroscience/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Computational neuroscience is an expanding field that is proving to be essential in neurosciences. The aim of this short intensive course will be to provide a common background in computational neuroscience. The course, after a brief historical overview of the field, will focus on the description of a few selected modelling and theoretical approaches that are currently developed, including details about their limits and advantages, and that can be applied to different scales of analysis (from the single neuron to the whole brain). In addition, we will provide a theoretical and a practical session on artificial neuronal networks of spiking neurons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Objectives: 	Understanding how computational modelling can be used to formulate and solve neuroscience problems at different spatial and temporal scales; learning the formal notions of information, encoding and decoding and experimenting their use on specific examples&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where: Marseille (France)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What: &lt;a href=&#34;https://ametice.univ-amu.fr/course/view.php?id=72868&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Session #3 : Realistic spiking neural networks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Computational Neuroscience Tutorial&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Friday, April 23, 2021; 9:00-12:30&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Objective: Applying the Theory on the eBrains platform&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/albertoarturovergani/CNT-2021&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://github.com/albertoarturovergani/CNT-2021&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hands-on practice&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Friday, April 23, 2021; 14:00-17:00&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Objective: replicating Mainen &amp;amp; Sejnowski (1995)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;github : &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/CONECT-INT/2021-04-23_PhDProgram-course-in-computational-neurosciences/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://github.com/CONECT-INT/2021-04-23_PhDProgram-course-in-computational-neurosciences/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AMETICE :  &lt;a href=&#34;https://ametice.univ-amu.fr/course/view.php?id=72868#section-4&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://ametice.univ-amu.fr/course/view.php?id=72868#section-4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;hands-on-session-reproduction-of-the-article-by-mainen--sejnowski-1995&#34;&gt;Hands-on session: reproduction of the article by Mainen &amp;amp; Sejnowski, 1995&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The aim of this task is to read a scientific article, to reproduce it with simulations of a neuron and to improve the understanding of the study.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Modalities: students will organize themselves alone, in pairs or in triads to provide a brief in the form of a &lt;a href=&#34;https://jupyter.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;notebook&lt;/a&gt; completed from &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/CONECT-INT/2021-04_PhDProgram-neurosciences-computationnelles/master/MainenSejnowski1995.ipynb&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;the model that is provided&lt;/a&gt;. Follow the &lt;code&gt;QUESTION&lt;/code&gt; tags in the notebook to guide you in this writing. Comments should be made in the notebook (don&amp;rsquo;t forget to save your changes).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tools needed: &lt;a href=&#34;https://jupyter.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Jupyter&lt;/a&gt;, with &lt;a href=&#34;https://numpy.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;numpy&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://matplotlib.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;matplotlib&lt;/a&gt;. These are standard tools and are easily installed on any platform. Other hosted solutions exist:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.ebrains.eu/bin/view/Collabs/neuromorphic/SpiNNaker/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;ebrains / HBP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://deepnote.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://deepnote.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;on &lt;a href=&#34;https://colab.research.google.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;GoogleColab&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://colab.research.google.com/github/CONECT-INT/2021-04_PhDProgram-neurosciences-computationnelles/blob/master/MainenSejnowski1995.ipynb&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://colab.research.google.com/github/CONECT-INT/2021-04_PhDProgram-neurosciences-computationnelles/blob/master/MainenSejnowski1995.ipynb&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;context&#34;&gt;context&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The goal of this first task is to create a &amp;ldquo;raster plot&amp;rdquo; that shows the reproducibility of a spike train with repetitions of the same stimulus, as in this work in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://laurentperrinet.github.io/2019-04-03_a_course_on_vision_and_modelization/#/1/3&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;rodent retina&lt;/a&gt; or in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://laurentperrinet.github.io/2019-04-03_a_course_on_vision_and_modelization/#/1/6&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;cat cortex (V1)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here, we will attempt to replicate Figure 1 of &lt;a href=&#34;http://citeseerx.ist.psu.edu/viewdoc/download?doi=10.1.1.299.8560&amp;amp;rep=rep1&amp;amp;type=pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Mainen &amp;amp; Sejnowski (1995)&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-figure-1&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.stack.imgur.com/ixnrz.png&#34; alt=&#34;Mainen Sejnowski 1995&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      figure 1
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;getting-to-know-the-tools-numpy-and-matplotlib&#34;&gt;getting to know the tools: numpy and matplotlib&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;we are going to create vectors representing the dynamics of a value as a function of time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;for that, we create a vector `time&amp;rsquo; representing 1 second with a precision of dt=.5ms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;in a first step, we will create a plot of a spike, a slot &amp;amp; a sinusoid&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;problem-definition-leaky-integrate-and-fire-neuron&#34;&gt;problem definition: leaky-integrate and fire neuron&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;we will simulate 1 neuron for 2 seconds with a precision of dt=1ms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;for that, we use the equation of a leaky-IF&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;then we show its response to the stimuli created above&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;injection-of-a-noise&#34;&gt;injection of a noise&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As in figure 1 of Mainen &amp;amp; Sejnowski (1995), we add a noise to the current injection&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;this noise can be characterized by its amplitude and its characteristic time: what is the impact on the result?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;what happens when we include an internal noise to the dynamics of the neuron?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;appendices&#34;&gt;Appendices&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;an article to read about time in the brain: &lt;a href=&#34;https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/perrinet-19-temps/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://laurentperrinet.github.io/publication/perrinet-19-temps/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://theconversation.com/temps-et-cerveau-comment-notre-perception-nous-fait-voyager-dans-le-temps-127567&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;direct link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://laurentperrinet.github.io/talk/2019-04-18-jnlf/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;From illusions to visual hallucinations: a door on perception&lt;/a&gt; - (&lt;a href=&#34;https://laurentperrinet.github.io/2019-04-18_JNLF/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;slides&lt;/a&gt;) - article on visual perception: &lt;a href=&#34;https://laurentperrinet.github.io/post/2019-06-06-theconversation/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://laurentperrinet.github.io/post/2019-06-06-theconversation/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://theconversation.com/illusions-et-hallucinations-visuelles-une-porte-sur-la-perception-117389&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;direct link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://laurentperrinet.github.io/talk/2019-04-03-a-course-on-vision-and-modelization/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Modelling spiking neural networks using Brian, Nest and pyNN&lt;/a&gt; - (&lt;a href=&#34;https://laurentperrinet.github.io/2019-01-14_LACONEU/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;slides&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://laurentperrinet.github.io/talk/2018-03-26-cours-neuro-comp-fep/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Tutorial on predictive coding&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://laurentperrinet.github.io/talk/2017-06-30-telluride/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://laurentperrinet.github.io/talk/2017-06-30-telluride/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://laurentperrinet.github.io/sciblog/files/2017-06-30_Telluride.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://laurentperrinet.github.io/sciblog/files/2017-06-30_Telluride.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2020-09-11 : CONECT seminar - &#34;Feedforward and feedback processes in visual recognition&#34; (T Serre)</title>
      <link>https://conect-int.github.io/talk/2020-09-11-conect-seminar-feedforward-and-feedback-processes-in-visual-recognition-t-serre/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2020 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://conect-int.github.io/talk/2020-09-11-conect-seminar-feedforward-and-feedback-processes-in-visual-recognition-t-serre/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;During a seminar at the Institute of Neurosciences Timone in Marseille, &lt;a href=&#34;http://serre-lab.clps.brown.edu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Thomas Serre&lt;/a&gt; will present his recent work on &amp;ldquo;Feedforward and feedback processes in visual recognition&amp;rdquo;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Progress in deep learning has spawned great successes in many engineering applications. As a prime example, convolutional neural networks, a type of feedforward neural networks, are now approaching – and sometimes even surpassing – human accuracy on a variety of visual recognition tasks. In this talk, however, I will show that these neural networks and their recent extensions exhibit a limited ability to solve seemingly simple visual reasoning problems involving incremental grouping, similarity, and spatial relation judgments. Our group has developed a recurrent network model of classical and extra-classical receptive fields that is constrained by the anatomy and physiology of the visual cortex. The model was shown to account for diverse visual illusions providing computational evidence for a novel canonical circuit that is shared across visual modalities. I will show that this computational neuroscience model can be turned into a modern end-to-end trainable deep recurrent network architecture that addresses some of the shortcomings exhibited by state-of-the-art feedforward networks for solving complex visual reasoning tasks. This suggests that neuroscience may contribute powerful new ideas and approaches to computer science and artificial intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Dr. &lt;a href=&#34;http://serre-lab.clps.brown.edu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Thomas Serre&lt;/a&gt; is an Associate Professor in Cognitive Linguistic and Psychological Sciences and an affiliate of the Carney Institute for Brain Science at Brown University. He received a Ph.D. in Neuroscience from MIT in 2006 and an MSc in EECS from Télécom Bretagne (France) in 2000. His research seeks to understand the neural computations supporting visual perception and has been featured in the BBC series “Visions from the Future” and other news articles (The Economist, New Scientist, Scientific American, IEEE Computing in Science and Technology, Technology Review and Slashdot). Dr. Serre is the Faculty Director of the Center for Computation and Visualization and the Associate Director of the Initiative for Computation in Brain and Mind at Brown University. He also holds an International Chair in AI within the Artificial and Natural Intelligence Toulouse Institute (France). Dr. Serre has served as an area chair and a senior program committee member for top-tier machine learning and computer vision conferences including AAAI, CVPR, and NeurIPS. He is currently serving as a domain expert for IARPA’s Machine Intelligence from Cortical Networks (MICrONS) program and as a scientific advisor for Vium, Inc. He was the recipient of an NSF Early Career Award as well as DARPA’s Young Faculty Award and Director’s Award.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
