<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Matthieu Gilson | CONECT | Computational Neuroscience Center @ INT</title>
    <link>https://conect-int.github.io/authors/matthieu-gilson/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://conect-int.github.io/authors/matthieu-gilson/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Matthieu Gilson</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://conect-int.github.io/authors/matthieu-gilson/avatar_hu649687aaa067e9fe98cb8aa085fbad98_57526_270x270_fill_q75_lanczos_center.jpg</url>
      <title>Matthieu Gilson</title>
      <link>https://conect-int.github.io/authors/matthieu-gilson/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Actors of CONECT</title>
      <link>https://conect-int.github.io/post/actors-conect/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://conect-int.github.io/post/actors-conect/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Within the INT, many components of CONECT already exist, either carried by researchers in computational neurosciences or as themes strongly anchored in this field. A survey of the current situation reveals the existence of projects at different scales.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://conect-int.github.io/contact&#34;&gt;Contact&lt;/a&gt; us to be added!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;from the cellular to the network level
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;deciphering the biophysical principles underlying robustness of neuronal activity using quantitative genotype-to-phenotype mapping strategies and realistic neuronal model databases (&lt;strong&gt;Jean-Marc Goaillard&lt;/strong&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;dynamics and function of small and large-scale neural networks: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://conect-int.github.io/authors/laurent-u-perrinet/&#34;&gt;Laurent Perrinet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; with &lt;a href=&#34;../../author/frederic-y-chavane&#34;&gt;Frédéric Chavane&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://conect-int.github.io/authors/matthieu-gilson/&#34;&gt;Matthieu Gilson&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;from networks to mesoscopic levels :
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bayesian inference and predictive process models (&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../../author/anna-montagnini&#34;&gt;Anna Montagnini&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;../../author/emmanuel-dauce&#34;&gt;Emmanuel Daucé&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://conect-int.github.io/authors/laurent-u-perrinet/&#34;&gt;Laurent Perrinet&lt;/a&gt;), reinforcement learning, action selection, decision &lt;a href=&#34;../../author/andrea-brovelli&#34;&gt;Andrea Brovelli&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;../../author/emmanuel-dauce&#34;&gt;Emmanuel Daucé&lt;/a&gt;), link with attentional mechanisms (Guilhem Ibos)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;information theory and functional connectivity for the analysis of cognitive brain networks (&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../../author/andrea-brovelli&#34;&gt;Andrea Brovelli&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://conect-int.github.io/authors/matthieu-gilson/&#34;&gt;Matthieu Gilson&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;../../author/bruno-giordano&#34;&gt;Bruno Giordano&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;deep learning for data processing (&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../../author/bruno-giordano&#34;&gt;Bruno Giordano&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;), deep learning + neuroimaging (&lt;em&gt;in voice perception&lt;/em&gt;) (Charly Lamothe) computational neuroscience and data processing in neuroinformatics (Sylvain Takerkart, NIT platform)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;at brain level
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;brain anatomy, particularly as applied to the formation of cortical folding (Julien Lefèvre with Guillaume Auzias, Sylvain Takerkart and &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../../author/olivier-coulon&#34;&gt;Olivier Coulon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;),&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the development of prognostic models of the evolution of certain pathologies (Lionel Velly, &lt;strong&gt;Sylvain Takerkart&lt;/strong&gt;),&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;develop the collaboration of theoretical neurosciences with neuroinformatics, notably with the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.int.univ-amu.fr/spip.php?page=plateform&amp;amp;equipe=CRISE&amp;amp;lang=fr&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;NIT&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;strong&gt;Sylvain Takerkart&lt;/strong&gt;, Guillaume Auzias)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A structuring of these different components through a center (independent of existing and future teams) would be a major asset to reach a new stage in the creation of INT³.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Objectives of CONECT</title>
      <link>https://conect-int.github.io/post/objectives-conect/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://conect-int.github.io/post/objectives-conect/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Computational Neuroscience Center (CONECT) is an incubator within the INT to promote theoretical and computational neuroscience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It ambitions to contribute to the training of a new generation of neuroscientists, following the revolution experienced by neuroscience over the past decades: tremendous technological advances across several disciplines have dramatically expanded the frontiers of experimentally accessible neuro-scientific facts. CONECT is thus concerned with new analysis tools and models that can account for large and complex datasets, in parallel with the NeuroTech Center that focuses on experimental devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CONECT aims to build an inter-disciplinary community within the INT to foster interactions between computational neuroscientists and with experimentalists. The tools include scientific animation (journal clubs, seminars) and practical sessions to leanr and master new tools. This will participate in structuring the teaching and research environment around computational neuroscience around AMU beyond INT alone. The plan is to involve not only local research partners of INT like NeuroMarseille and the Laennec Institute, but also engineer schools (PolyTech, Centrale Marseille) and applied mathematics masters.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
