<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fanny Cazettes | CONECT | Computational Neuroscience Center @ INT</title>
    <link>https://conect-int.github.io/authors/fanny-cazettes/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://conect-int.github.io/authors/fanny-cazettes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Fanny Cazettes</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 15:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://conect-int.github.io/authors/fanny-cazettes/avatar_hu3acbc8ee0028411060c2a8e5f1f715f0_12350_270x270_fill_q75_lanczos_center.jpg</url>
      <title>Fanny Cazettes</title>
      <link>https://conect-int.github.io/authors/fanny-cazettes/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>2024-03-11 : CONECT seminar by Danny Burnham</title>
      <link>https://conect-int.github.io/talk/2024-03-11-conect-seminar-by-danny-burnham/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://conect-int.github.io/talk/2024-03-11-conect-seminar-by-danny-burnham/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When: Monday, Marche 11th &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;14:30 to 16:00&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Where: &lt;em&gt;salle Laurent Vinay&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During this CONECT seminar, &lt;a href=&#34;https://ion.uoregon.edu/about/person-page/277&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Danny Burnham&lt;/a&gt; will present his recent work on &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;Mice alternate between inference- and stimulus-bound strategies during probabilistic foraging&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract : Essential features of the world are often hidden and must be inferred by constructing internal models based on indirect evidence. During foraging, animals must continually choose between trying to exploit a depleting food source at their current location and leaving to explore a new source at the expense of costly travel epochs. In a deterministic environment, the optimal strategy is to leave the current site when the immediate rate of reward drops below the average rate - a stimulus-bound strategy, assigning each action a value that is updated based on its immediate outcome. This strategy, however, is not optimal in a realistic foraging scenario, where rewards are encountered probabilistically and the optimal strategy is inference-bound, requiring the animal to infer the hidden structure of the world. Motivated by recent studies showing that mice alternate between discrete strategies during perceptual decision-making, we test the hypothesis that mouse behavior during a probabilistic foraging task switches between inference- and stimulus-bound strategies within the same session. To this end, we developed a novel hidden Markov model with linear emissions (LM-HMM) to capture this switching dynamic. When applied to mice engaged in the task, the LM-HMM revealed that mice switch between distinct inference bound and stimulus bound strategies exhibiting varying impulsivities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Danny Burnham is a computational neuroscientist from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://ion.uoregon.edu/about/person-page/277&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Institute of Neuroscience at the university of Oregon&lt;/a&gt; interested in Artificial Neural Network models of learning and memory.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
